#### AHMAD FIQRI OEMRY

## **Data Science and Analysist**

Medan, Indonesia | 082160945033 | foemry@gmail.com | linkedin | github | portfolio website

#### SUMMARY

Mechanical Engineering graduate with **5 years experience** in inspection and quality management. Recently completed Purwadhika Digital School's Digital Talent Incubator for data science and machine learning program with specializing in python and tableau also having skills on web development with javascript, React and node.js. Switching Career and eager to kickstart a career in tech, I bring **strong analytical thinking**, **solid team-working** and **good understanding**. Open to entry level opportunities that will allow me to apply my capabilities, grow professionally and make a positive impact related with data.

#### **EDUCATION**

Purwadhika Digital School - Batam, Indonesia

March, 2024 - Oct, 2024

Digital Talent Incubator program as Data science and machine learning

Final Score: 86.18

University of North Sumatera - Medan, Indonesia

Aug, 2011 - Sept, 2016

**Bachelor Degree of Mechanical Engineering** 

GPA 3.09 / 4.00

#### **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

## PT. Radiant Utama Interinsco, Tbk - Palembang, Indonesia

Oct, 2023 - Jan, 2024

Quality Inspector

Overhaul Project PT. Kilang Pertamina International RU3:

- Perform Inspection and Quality Control activities during fabrication process based on parameter and standard
- Coordinating with team to perform the Test and reviewing the Non Destructive Test Result along with report

# PT. Moehringer Palmwood Indonesia - Medan, Indonesia

Nov, 2022 - Sept, 2023

Site Controller

- Perform Surveilance, Inspection and Quality Control during the project
- Developing a bill of quantities for project operational needs

# PT. Radiant Utama Interinsco, Tbk - Balongan, Indonesia

Oct, 2021 - Nov, 2022

Quality Inspector

Turnaround Project PT. Kilang Pertamina International VI:

- Perform Inspection and Quality Control activities during fabrication process based on parameter and standard
- Coordinating with team to perform the Test and reviewing the Non Destructive Test Result along with report

### PT. Sucofindo Persero – Jakarta, Indonesia

Jan, 2019 - Sept, 2022

Technical Inspector and Surveyor

- Perform review and verification for the import document.
- Perform Inspection and survey for the imported goods in accordance with documents and regulations.
- Conducting inspection, survey and audit for factory in accordance with documents and regulations.
- Consulting with client and make the related report based on inspection and survey result.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS AND SOFT SKILLS**

**Technical skills:** Data analysist, Tableau, R, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Tailwindcss, Node.js, PHP, Figma, Web Development.

**Soft skills:** Problem Solving, Time Management, Attention to Detail, Analytical Thinking and Teamwork, Quality Check and inspection

Languages: Bahasa (Native), English (Intermediate - Advanced).

### • Olist Brazilian Ecommerce Recommendation System | Team-Project

Developed a recommendation system for Olist, a Brazilian ecommerce platform. Collaborated with a team to analyze customer behavior and product data, implementing machine learning algorithms to suggest personalized products. Utilized Python, Pandas, Scikit-learn, and collaborative filtering techniques to enhance user engagement and sales.

## • Interior Company Landing page | Self-Project

Designed and developed a landing page for an interior design company. Focused on aesthetic design and user experience to showcase the company's portfolio and services. Implemented using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for smooth interactions and responsive design.

project link

### • Ecommerce Customer Churn prediction | Self-Project

Built a machine learning model to predict customer churn for an ecommerce platform. Conducted data preprocessing, feature selection, and model optimization. Utilized Python, Pandas, Scikit-learn, and RandomizedSearchCV for hyperparameter tuning.

project link

### • AirBnB Bangkok Listing Data Analysist | Self-Project

Analyzed AirBnB listing data for Bangkok to uncover insights into pricing strategies, popular neighborhoods, and guest preferences. Cleaned and visualized data using Python, Pandas, Matplotlib, and Seaborn, producing actionable insights for hosts.

project\_link

### • Front end simple marketplace website | self-Project

Developed a front end of marketplace website to sellings various stuff. Focusing on front-end development and user interface design, ensuring a seamless shopping experience. Utilized html, tailwindcss, reactjs to create a responsive layouts.

project\_link

#### • Full stack ecommerce website | Team-Project

Collaborated in a team to develop a full-stack ecommerce platform. Worked on both front-end and back-end, integrating payment gateways and user authentication. Used React.js, Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB to create a dynamic and scalable application.

project link

### COURSE, TRAINING AND CERTIFICATION

#### Purwadhika Digital talent Incubator - Batam, Indonesia

March, 2024 - October, 2024

Data Science and machine Learning

Relevant Course works: Python, Tableau, Data & Business Analysis, Machine Learnin, SQL

MySkill - Batam, Indonesia | Online Learning

Feb. 2024 - March, 2024

UI/ UX Designer Bootcamp

- Final Project: Revamp McDonald App.
- Relevant Course works : Figma

Revou.com - Medan, Indonesia | Online Learning

Jan, 2024 - Feb, 2024

Data Analysis 10 days course

Relevant Course works: Tableau, Python, business Analysis

Harisenin.com - Medan, Indonesia | Online Learning

Nov, 2022 - April, 2023

Full Stack Developer Bootcamp

- Final Project: Designed and developed an eccomerce website within two months
  - Relevant Course works: HTML, Tailwindcss, CSS, MySQL, JavaScript, React and Node.js